picfair.com 2019-12-02

# Privacy Policy | Picfair

**Last Updated 24 May 1018**

### Who we are, and what is this?

We're Picfair, a company that wants to help photographers make money from their creativity. Our offices are at 154-158 Shoreditch High St, London E1 6HU. Our registered address is 5 New Street Square, London, EC4A 3TW - that's the address of our Company Secretary, who are also our lawyers Taylor Wessing. They always forward on any correspondence they receive for us at that address, but if you want to get hold of us quickly, or send us postcards (and please do), the Shoreditch High Street address is the most direct route. Quicker still, you can always email us, about anything, at [hello@picfair.com](mailto:hello@picfair.com). 

This Privacy Policy is our way to try to explain as clearly as possible exactly how we use and collect your data. We've tried to explain and collate as much as possible, but if there's anything we need to add or amend, we reserve the right to make changes to it it, without giving you notice, whenever we need to. But it will always be here, on our website, if you ever want to check for updates. 

Importantly, if you ever wish to request any personal information we hold on you, you can do that whenever you like, by emailing [datarequest@picfair.com](mailto:datarequest@picfair.com). 

### Collection of personal information

#### 1\. Browsing Picfair

You can browse Picfair's millions of beautiful images from across the globe without logging in or submitting any personal information. 

We use a number of analytic products to track visitor behaviour on our site, because we're always trying to make Picfair as useful as possible. This means we monitor things like clicks, your Internet Protocol (IP) address, browser types, CPU speed, site performance, operating systems and device types, time spent on pages, time and time zone, the page that referred you to us, Internet Service Providers, and pages viewed. We use this information to analyse trends and improve site functionality on an individual and aggregate basis. 

These analytic services rely on software such as cookies. Cookies are small, unique text files that a website sends to your computer when you visit a site and do things on it - these can be session cookies which terminate when you close a browser, or persistent cookies which will remain until you delete them. For example, we use a persistent cookie for your login, so that you don't need to log in every time you visit Picfair. You can always easily delete all cookies that a website is using by deleting them in your browser settings. 

Here's the services we use when you browse Picfair (this also applies to logged-in users too): 

  * Papertrail \- this keeps a temporary record of any page that loads on Picfair, and how it loads (i.e. "it loaded!", or "Oh no it didn't load!". We use it to look out for any pages that are broken so we can fix them.) 
  * Honeybadger \- we use this to tell us if a page is definitely broken. It's like Papertrail's "bad news only" cousin. 
  * NewRelic \- this monitors the overall performance of the site, especially page speed. If a page is taking 17 years to load, we need to know about it. 
  * Google Firebase \- we use this to count the "pic views" on images, so we can let our photographers know which of their images are the most popular. It's a very fancy way of counting from one to a billion. 
  * Google Analytics \- this is "web analytics" stuff above - anonymous for users that are not signed in but identifiable for those who are signed in. 
  * Social Media analytics (Facebook and LinkedIn) 
  * Hotjar \- Page heatmaps and feedback collection

#### 2\. Using Picfair as a photographer, image buyer, print buyer, and assignment client

##### a. Social sign in

You can sign up to Picfair using Facebook and Twitter - this uses some information that these services already have in order to speed up your sign up process (and so that you can log in with a single click via these services in the future). This includes your first name, last name, and email address. 

##### b. Profile information

Whether you are a photographer, an image buyer, a print customer, or an assignment client, once you are signed up to Picfair you may be asked for any of the following information: 

  * Contact information such as your name, email address, and phone number 
  * Billing information such as your credit or debit card number, expiration date, and billing address 
  * Profile information such as your username, password, location, job title, photography specialisations and qualifications, company name, social media accounts, VAT number, profile bio 
  * Delivery information - your postal address 
  * Payout methods including paypal addresses, and British bank account sort codes and account numbers

In order to reduce errors and to authenticate our users and clients, we may from time to time use publicly accessible third-party sources to supplement the information you give us in order ensure the veracity of our records. 

##### c. Uploading images

When you upload images to Picfair, we ask you to add a title, caption, tags and price. We also analyse the image file itself for any technical or descriptive information - this may be in the format of EXIF, IPTC or other data protocols. Please note that this information will be stored by Picfair, and may be viewable by image customers and our distribution partners. 

### Changing & requesting your information

Your profile information is always accessible and editable in the "Dashboard' section of your account. Information relating to orders, cashouts, and deliveries are stored on our databases to ensure that we can reference any such orders, cashouts or deliveries should a problem arise. 

As with everything relating to your privacy on Picfair, you can request to view any information we have stored by emailing [datarequest@picfair.com](mailto:datarequest@picfair.com). 

### Storing your information

Information gathered as described in **b.** and **c.** above are stored as followed: 

  * Your profile information, contact information, delivery information, billing information and payout request information are stored in our core database on Heroku. 
  * Your images, including all of their metadata, are stored on Cloudinary, with a backup copy on AWS
  * Your contact information is stored by Sendgrid and Mailchimp, so that we can get in contact with you 

### Protecting your personal information

The information you provide to Picfair is protected as follows: 

The Personal Information that you provide in connection with the use of the Site is protected in several ways. 

Access by you to your account profile is available through a password and unique customer ID / email selected by you. This password is encrypted. You should strive to use a strong, alpha-numeric password which you should not divulge to anyone or reuse on other websites. 

Your Personal Information resides with databases run by Heroku who have a comprehensive security policy: [www.heroku.com/policy/security](https://www.heroku.com/policy/security). Your Personal Information is encrypted whenever it is transmitted to Picfair. We do not store your payment card details, although our payment provider (Stripe) may store them if you choose. 

We strive to protect the Personal Information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. However, no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure. While we take into account the sensitivity of the Personal Information we collect, process and store, and the current state of technology to use these measures protect your Personal Information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. 

If you have any questions about security on our Web Sites, you can send email to us at hello@picfair.com. 

### How we use your personal information

Picfair collects your information in order to comply with our legal obligations, to provide you with products, and to improve our service to you. We do not sell or seek to make money from your personally identifiable information. Here are the way we use your information: 

  * To confirm product purchases and deliver invoices and receipts 
  * To confirm that cashout requests have been processed 
  * To notify you of, and confirm, actions you have taken on the site 
  * To alert you to significant changes on the website 
  * To alert you to significant changes to the company 
  * To confirm image licence allocation and notify of image purchases and rewards 
  * To alert you to any website or company changes that require your attention 
  * To keep you informed about special offers and services 
  * To investigate any alleged breaches of our Contributors Agreements, Licence Agreements, or general terms of service 
  * To customise your experience of our website, including targeting offerings and services to you 
  * To meet our service development needs and in improving the performance of the website 
  * To welcome you to the site and confirm your account 
  * To allow you to opt in or opt out of marketing correspondence 
  * To respond to your customer service queries

### Data Retention

Information collected by Picfair will be stored for as long as you hold an account. If you wish to delete your account please contact [hello@picfair.com](mailto:hello@picfair.com). When an account deletion request is received, we will delete/anonymise your account, excluding transaction information (i.e. sales & purchases). 

### Advertising Activities

Information collected from users help us create interesting and tailor-made advertising for you elsewhere on the web. Picfair collects information in a pseudonymised way - including information on your computer and Internet access, operating system as well as platform, date and time of your visit or products viewed.This is done using cookies stored on your computer that make identifying a pseudonymised user possible without any reference to your personal data. 

This data collection is used to carry our user-based advertising campaigns on the following platforms: 

Google, Inc. – Information on data protection with Google can be found here: <http://www.google.com/intl/de/policies/privacy/>

LinkedIn - Information on data protection with LinkedIn can be found here: <https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy>

Facebook Inc. - Information on data protection with Facebook Inc. can be found here: <https://www.facebook.com/full_data_use_policy>

If you do not wish to receive user-based advertising material, you can object to it through your preferences on the the respective platforms. In your browser settings you can adjust the usage restrictions for all third-party cookies. 

### 3rd Parties

Picfair does not use any 3rd party services that collect your information that do not perform core functionalities of our website or products. The 3rd Parties we use that are not already referenced in this Privacy Policy are as follows: 

  * Stripe: This is our payment processing company 
  * Cloudflare \- This is a website wrapper that protects against cyber attacks 
  * Zendesk \- This helps us gather and process customer queries 
  * BrickFTP \- this helps us ingest and process large collections of images and their metadata

### Links to 3rd Party Sites

Our site includes many links to 3rd party sites, including the personal websites of many of our photographers. If you submit any personal information to these sites, your information is not protected by this Privacy Policy. 

### Opting Out

You can opt out of any Picfair newsletters by clicking on the "email preferences" section of your account, or by clicking on the "unsubscribe" options contained within any newsletters that you recieve. This will not opt you out of any non-promotional emails that Picfair sends you, such as, but not limited to, changes to our Privacy Policy, General Terms, Contributor Agreements, Licence Agreements, service-related announcements, emails triggered by actions on the site, registration emails, notifications relating to significant changes to core Picfair products or services, and any of the other legitimate interests listed above. If you wish to not receive any of these emails, you can choose to delete your account by emailing [hello@picfair.com](mailto:hello@picfair.com)
